<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- This grammar has been deprecated - use FMPXMLRESULT instead --><FMPDSORESULT xmlns="http://www.filemaker.com/fmpdsoresult"><ERRORCODE>0</ERRORCODE><DATABASE>EHEM_Database-Enkleistra-v.1.07.fmp12</DATABASE><LAYOUT></LAYOUT><ROW MODID="1" RECORDID="49"><mk_ArchPhase_ID>-AP00005</mk_ArchPhase_ID><ArchPhase_UUIDNumber>1291156950944029457094735512775779137417598515882032712240</ArchPhase_UUIDNumber><Name>Phase One</Name><Date>1160-1170</Date><Date_range></Date_range><Description>The first digital three D model which is currently developed by the CYENS multidisciplinary team is based on this hypothetical plan showcasing the Hermitage on the 24th of June in 1160, one year after Neophytos found the cave on the feast day of Saint John the Baptist. Over this first year of his stay at Tala, he himself transformed this cave into his ascetic retreat, even carving his own tomb out of rock and creating an altar. On the 14th of September in 1160, feast day of the discovery of the Holy Cross by Saint Helena, he dedicated the altar to the Holy Cross. In the east curtain wall, enclosing the Enkleistra, the surviving arched window may betray the existence of a door opening just below it - although no traces of it survive today.</Description><Promoter></Promoter><Monument_ID></Monument_ID><Notes></Notes><Links><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></Links><Code_counter>AP00005</Code_counter></ROW><ROW MODID="1" RECORDID="50"><mk_ArchPhase_ID>-AP00006</mk_ArchPhase_ID><ArchPhase_UUIDNumber>1982445831502071003630277974781214979879524283415136837891</ArchPhase_UUIDNumber><Name>Phase Two</Name><Date>1170 - 1183</Date><Date_range></Date_range><Description>The second phase - drawn here in light blue - is concerned with the period between around 1170 when Neophytos was ordained priest by the Bishop Basilieios Kinnamos of Paphos and 1183 when the Enkleistra began then to develop into a small regular monastery, a cenobium; with the establishment of a small number of monks and the help of a subsidy provided by the bishop to meet the extra expenses involved. In this phase and most possibly just after 1170, the partition wall was built, maybe, to separate his cell from the rest of the Enkleistra - as he named it in Greek - making his cell private and essentially confining himself. Beside his bed shelf, desk and niches, a wall painting is inscribed: with the year 1183 which corresponds to an early - if not the earliest - painting campaign and with the name of its artist Theodoros Apsudes. In this campaign, the extraordinary painting with Neophytos between Archangels is also ascribed. By 1183, the possible entrance to his cell must have been sealed with masonry based on its adornment with murals. By the same year, the western part of the Enkleistra was at least partially carved and painted as well. </Description><Promoter></Promoter><Monument_ID></Monument_ID><Notes></Notes><Links><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></Links><Code_counter>AP00006</Code_counter></ROW><ROW MODID="0" RECORDID="51"><mk_ArchPhase_ID>-AP00007</mk_ArchPhase_ID><ArchPhase_UUIDNumber>5610627161515693007995708923905863599478002145339670580009</ArchPhase_UUIDNumber><Name>Phase Three</Name><Date>1183 - 1214</Date><Date_range></Date_range><Description>he third phase deals with the period between after 1183 and 1214 - drawn here in orange. By 1196, a notable part of the Enkleistra’s expansion was completed. Its cave refectory and cave church of the Holy Cross were formed in their current shape. 1 The former entrance to the Enkleistra was enlarged. This opening may have now closed only by low parapet slabs, dividing the bema from the naos. The niche in the west wall of the bema may have functioned as the prothesis niche; for the painted cryptograms in it stand for a text recited in the Presanctified ritual which typically took place in the Prothesis. In the naos, two late twelfth-century icons of Virgin Mary and Christ - painted on wood - flank these slabs. These icons are now displayed in the Museum of the Holy Monastery of Saint Neophytos. [p. 7] The Neophytos’ typikon of 1211, that is the second testamentary rule of the Enkleistra, mentions that wall paintings were added in his twenty-fourth year from his confinement, which would have been in 1196 - if we accept the year of his confinement in 1172. This date corresponds with the information provided by a later painted inscription of 1503 recording the year of the completion of the mural decoration of the church. The decorative programme of this painting campaign from Neophytos’ lifetime is still preserved to a significant extent. In the naos, Neophytos displayed the cross relic he had acquired in an east-facing niche, accommodating a wooden cross with a cavity at its centre - today at the same museum. Above and flanking the cross are two archangels dressed as liturgical deacons, and above them, appropriately, is a mural of the Crucifixion of Christ. An Hagioscope, namely a shaft on the vault of the church - beside its entrance - opened to connect the latter with the Hagiasterion of Neophytos on the upper storey, from where he attended the liturgy. [p. 8] The development of the complex in multiple levels along the cliff offers distinct challenges in the creation of the 3D models. [p. 9] In the post-1196 expansion sub-phase, Neophytos’ new cell dedicated to New Zion and the cell of Saint John the Baptist were hollowed up higher up the cliff in the top level of the Enkleistra. Two curved structures were also hallowed up one above the other and just to the left of the occasional torrent, on the first and second level of the 2 Enkleistra. All these rock-cut structures responded to the needs of the monastic community which was established around Neophytos. By 1214 - the year of the official declaration of Neophytos’ second Typikon, it is known that his monastery allowed up to fifteen or even eighteen monks and monk Esaias, Neophytos’ nephew was its priest. [p. 10] In the Holy Cross church, the figure of a monk beside stylites saints in this painting campaign has been read as either Neophytos or Esaias </Description><Promoter></Promoter><Monument_ID></Monument_ID><Notes></Notes><Links><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></Links><Code_counter>AP00007</Code_counter></ROW><ROW MODID="0" RECORDID="52"><mk_ArchPhase_ID>-AP00008</mk_ArchPhase_ID><ArchPhase_UUIDNumber>4799491175437881993796249127178280401953198192277517109597</ArchPhase_UUIDNumber><Name>Phase Four</Name><Date>1214 -1502/3</Date><Date_range></Date_range><Description>The fourth phase is concerned with the period after the death of Neophytos in around 1215. Fulfilling his testament, his tomb, in his initial cell at the site, was walled off - as is here drawn in green. The addition of a pointed stone arch in the exterior east wall, enclosing the Neopthytos’ tomb could coincide with the first major restoration of the Enkleistra and its wall paintings in 1502/3, based on its similarity with other contemporary remnants from Cyprus. In this painting campaign, belongs for example the Pantokrator on the ceiling of the bema. At the time of this restoration - but before the aforementioned repainting, a templon, with one opening in its centre, must have incorporated not only the earlier low parapet slabs but also the two aforementioned icons. This arrangement of the icons was recorded before the restoration works of 1963 at the monument by the Dumbarton Oaks in collaboration with the Cyprus Department of Antiquities. Within the EHEM project, visualisation applications aspire to integrate these bilateral icons in the hypothetical 3D models showing their different placement in the third and fourth phase of the Enkleistra </Description><Promoter></Promoter><Monument_ID></Monument_ID><Notes></Notes><Links><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></Links><Code_counter>AP00008</Code_counter></ROW></FMPDSORESULT>